<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://iniyamuraari.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://iniyamuraari.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-10-08T22:23:33+00:00</updated><id>https://iniyamuraari.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Iniya Muraari&apos;s personal website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My Arangetram Experience</title><link href="https://iniyamuraari.github.io/blog/2024/arangetram/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Arangetram Experience"/><published>2024-08-25T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-25T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://iniyamuraari.github.io/blog/2024/arangetram</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://iniyamuraari.github.io/blog/2024/arangetram/"><![CDATA[<p>I have been learning classical Indian dance - Bharatanatyam - for 13 years. I finally performed my arangetram this summer – an event that marks the culmination of years of dedication and the beginning of my journey as a classical dancer. The word “arangetram” translates to “ascending the stage”, symbolizing a dancer’s solo debut and a tradition that celebrates both the dancer’s progress and the art form itself.</p> <p><strong>The Preparation</strong></p> <p>I began rehearsing for my arangetram three years ago, with the original plan to complete it in the summer of 2023. However, with A-levels approaching fast, I decided to postpone the event to the following summer to allow myself more time to practice and enjoy the process. This decision turned out to be a blessing because it gave me the space to focus and fully immerse myself in the preparation.</p> <p>Before starting university, I had weekly lessons with my dance teacher. Once I started my studies, though, finding a space to practice in proved difficult. I ended up using the university squash courts as my rehearsal space! It was quite a challenge, but I managed to keep up with online lessons during term time and in-person sessions whenever I visited home.</p> <p>The real preparation began last summer, during my trip to India. Scouring sari shops for the perfect costumes became an adventure in itself. Eventually, we finally found the perfect saris, and I had four beautiful costumes tailored and stitched for the big day. Wearing those heavy pieces of jewellery, false hair, and layers of makeup was a painful process – but the end result was magical.</p> <p><strong>The Photoshoot</strong></p> <p>The photoshoot made the event feel real. We scheduled it around Easter to create the perfect invites and brochures for the event. The nerves set in, but the photographer was warm and encouraging, and as the session progressed, I began to relax and truly enjoy the moment. The photos turned out beautifully and became a lovely preview of what was to come.</p> <p><strong>The Repertoire</strong></p> <p>For my arangetram, I learned eight dances in total. These dances covered both Nritta (technical dance movements) and Natya (expressions and storytelling), showcasing various Hindu myths; many of which I remember fondly from my childhood. I was incredibly fortunate to have a live orchestra accompanying me. My dance teacher was on the nattuvangam (rhythmic direction), and we had artists playing the mridangam (a type of drum), flute, veena, and vocals. There’s something so special about dancing to live music – it adds an extra layer of connection between the dancer, the musicians, and the audience.</p> <p><strong>The Big Day</strong></p> <p>The day itself went by very quickly. It almost felt like it didn’t happen! My friends and family played such an important role in making sure the event ran smoothly. My sister, in particular, did a beautiful job as the compère, guiding the audience through each performance and the story behind it. My parents were the true masterminds behind the event, working tirelessly to organize everything down to the finest detail. I’m also deeply grateful to my grandparents, aunt, and cousin, who flew from India just to see me perform. Their presence was heartwarming and made the day even more special.</p> <p>Each performance required a quick costume change, and my friends were there every step of the way, helping me switch costumes, reapply makeup, and adjust jewellery. While I was physically exhausted by the end of it – performing in heavy costumes with layers of jewellery is no small feat – the energy and excitement carried me through. The moment I ascended the stage and performed my first dance, all the hard work felt worth it.</p> <p><strong>Reflections</strong></p> <p>Looking back, the arangetram was more than just a performance; it was the culmination of years of learning, dedication, and the support of everyone around me. I am deeply thankful for the guidance of my teacher, who has nurtured my love for dance since the beginning, and for the encouragement of my family and friends, without whom this journey would not have been possible.</p> <p>The arangetram isn’t just an ending but a beginning – it marks the point where I’m no longer just a student but an artist ready to embrace more challenges and opportunities. While the preparation was gruelling and the event itself physically demanding, it has left me with beautiful memories, and the realization that with dedication, anything is possible.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="dance,"/><category term="extra-curricular"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Completing my dream]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lessons for a first year Computing student</title><link href="https://iniyamuraari.github.io/blog/2024/lessons/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lessons for a first year Computing student"/><published>2024-07-02T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-02T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://iniyamuraari.github.io/blog/2024/lessons</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://iniyamuraari.github.io/blog/2024/lessons/"><![CDATA[<p>Starting university can be both exciting and overwhelming. Between coding assignments, making new friends, and just generally keeping yourself alive, university will be a challenge, but I hope my advice helps you navigate your first year.</p> <ol> <li>Start your coursework early and allocate a little bit of time every day to it. It is a lot less stressful than cramming it all the night before, and you will not understand the work as well.</li> <li>Turn up to lectures, and figure out how you best learn. I can’t just listen to lectures because I zone out, and using Notion on my laptop often means I get distracted, so handwritten notes are the best technique for me. Be aware that each lecturer works differently - if they don’t have a clear, concise set of notes you can understand, make your own (either inside the lecture or in your own time).</li> <li>Start revising early, too! Emphasise doing practice questions and past papers. Despite the learning methods being different, university is a lot like school, and the same revision techniques will work.</li> <li>Give yourself time to rest. Especially if you live in student accomodation, you will find someone going out every night.</li> <li>Don’t feel like you have to join them unless you want to - forcing yourself will only lead to a bad night out.</li> <li>Don’t feel bad if you find university hard. You have to study the same amount as high school (with less structure too), feed yourself, make friends, and join societies. As you progress, you’ll settle down into a routine and feel more comfortable. Reach out to your friends, family and university resources when you need help.</li> <li>Computer science students are well known for having no hobbies that don’t involve a screen. Break the stereotype and touch some grass once in a while.</li> <li>Stack overflow is your best friend.</li> <li>Enjoy your year. You will look back at this time fondly and wish you hadn’t taken it for granted.</li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="computing,"/><category term="university"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to make the most of your first year at university]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Volunteering at IC Hack</title><link href="https://iniyamuraari.github.io/blog/2024/ichack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Volunteering at IC Hack"/><published>2024-03-17T00:32:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-17T00:32:13+00:00</updated><id>https://iniyamuraari.github.io/blog/2024/ichack</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://iniyamuraari.github.io/blog/2024/ichack/"><![CDATA[<p>IC hack - the largest student run hackathon in Europe, hosted by Imperial’s own Computing society and my first hackathon experience. Unfortunately, tickets to compete were very hard to come by, so I had to volunteer so I wouldn’t miss out on the biggest event of the year. The biggest perk of IC Hack had to be the insane sponsors. This year we had Marshall Wace, Citadel, Optiver, Terra, Jane Street, JetBrains and more!</p> <p><strong>24 hours of coding</strong></p> <p>The hackathon began with a big welcome talk at Millenium conference centre, and I was on door duty, which ended up being pretty decent as I got to talk to all the sponsors as they arrived.</p> <p>As students flocked to the common rooms, we were in charge of handing out tote bags (and stealing some for ourselves). Luckily I had a friend also volunteering, so the boring jobs like setting chairs up became more fun.</p> <p>The main sponsors got to shape the event by picking the problems teams needed to solve. This made the hackathon all the more interesting, as the problems were designed around their industry, and students could access their APIs to create to their hearts desire.</p> <p><strong>Volunteering: behind the scenes</strong></p> <p>Even though I didn’t compete, volunteering gave me a cool perspective. I got to see how everything ran behind the scenes and help the event run smoothly (and I got a special volunteer’s green t-shirt which made me feel important). Thankfully, the volunteers had a schedule so I didn’t have to work the whole 24 hours, but there were many students who stayed up working on their solutions. My friend group decided to go home and they were definitely more productive after doing so.</p> <p>The constant flow of free food was enough to draw anyone to the event. They had pizza for the volunteers, as well as food trucks for everyone, ranging from burritos to bubble tea. There were tables filled to the brim with snacks and drinks, and I may have stolen too many cans of fanta lemon to take home.</p> <p><strong>Missed talks, but got involved with judging</strong></p> <p>One downside of volunteering instead of competing was that I didn’t get a chance to attend any of the sponsor talks. I definitely plan on making time for those next year.</p> <p>On the bright side, I did get to help Terra with the judging process, which turned out to be one of the most interesting parts of the event. Terra’s challenge focused on improving army performance, asking teams to develop solutions that could enhance the performance and safety of soldiers. It was fascinating to see the range of creative solutions the teams came up with.</p> <p>The winning project was a brilliant <em>**</em>scheduler, tracker, and forecaster for military personnel, offering a way to efficiently manage resources and predict needs in real time. It was a well-deserved win, but there were plenty of other standout ideas too.</p> <p>In my opinion, the most original idea was a mapping tool designed to help soldiers find the safest routes back to base in conflict zones, which may not be the same as the fastest route, especially if the soldier is injured. It combined real-time data with historical patterns to minimise risks on the battlefield, demonstrating how technology can be used in innovative ways to save lives.</p> <p><strong>Final thoughts and reflections</strong></p> <p>As fun as it was to volunteer, it’s hard not to feel a little jealous watching teams build incredible projects, get feedback from top-tier companies, and compete for the win. The experience was unforgettable, but I will be first in line to get a ticket next year.</p> <p>If you’re into tech and haven’t been to a hackathon yet, you should definitely try to attend one, whether as a participant or volunteer. You might even end up helping to shape the future of tech— or at the very least, leave with a backpack full of snacks!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="computing,"/><category term="hackathon,"/><category term="university"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My experience at the largest student-run hackathon in europe]]></summary></entry></feed>